Hello and welcome to real easy English.
The podcast where we have real conversations in easy English to help you learn.
I'm Neil.
and with me is Georgie.
Hello, did you know that you can now watch a video of this podcast and you can read along with a transcript on our website.
Visit BBC learningningenglish dot com.
Hi, Georgie, how are you I'm very well.
Thank you, Neil, How are you, How is your journey into work My journey into work was very good today actually, and we're actually talking about transport today,
How is your journey to work My journey was quite easy this morning actually it isn't always and Neil,
we actually have a very similar commute don't we I get the tube to work which in the UK is the underground train So I walked.
The station around15 to20 minutes.
And then I get the underground train, 1 train, and then I change, and then get another one.
And then I walk to work.
What about you, I do that, But before, before.
Your bit.
I have to get a bus as well.
Are you that far away from the station, a couple of miles, Okay, 3 kilomet,
a bit too far to walk, a bit too far to walk.
I have walked.
When the public transport has been unreliable, but normally I get the bus to the tube,
stop and then I get on the tube into work lovelyly.
And do you like the tube, What do you think about it, I think the tube is very convenient, actually,
because the trains go very frequently.
So if you miss one, you can.
Wait just a couple of minutes and get the next one and it's probably the quickest way to get into central London because there's so
much traffic driving is a really bad idea.
Yeah, I agree with you.
It is very reliable.
It's usually very easy.
The thing I don't like about it, especially in the morning at rush hour, is the number of people on the tube.
The underground trains in London are very old, they'are very small, and they are very crowded in the mornings,
so crowded means there's lots of people we can also say packed.
Yeah, and I really don't like being in a tight space with lots of people in the mornings so early in the morning Yeah,
I agree, but I'm lucky because I get on the tube.
At the first stop, so I always get a seat, but then by the time you get on, it is usually really packed and the closer you get into central London.
The more packed it is you're squashed up against strangers it's not always fun I hate it What about buses do you like buses?
Busees are okay, they in London again, they are quite frequent.
and that's convenient.
Not always.
I mean, they are.
They're frequent, but they're more unreliable than trains, aren't they?
There always seems to be road workss near where I live, And when there are road workss, there are traffic lights,
and then there are delays on the buses.
So in the city, public transport can be great, but what.
when we go outside of the city, what do you use to go to other parts of the UK if it's quite far,
so if I'm going really far north, maybe to Scotland or to I don't know, Manchester or a northern city,
it's probably better to get the train.
Because it's faster.
And I really like trains.
You can relax.
It's a relaxing experience.
Some of my best travel experiences have been on long distance trains.
yeah, yeah, can you.
Where have you been that's been so fantastic on a train Well, I once went from Prague to Moscow on a train.
Wow, Yeah, what was that like really exciting why?
It took about three days, and I was with some friends and we could eat and drink and look out the window.
The landscape changed frequently.
It was just exciting.
Let's recap the vocabulary we heard in this podcast starting with some useful adjectives
to describe public transport.
For example, we had crowded, which means very busy.
We also hear packed.
We had reliable, which describe something you can trust and unreliable, which describe something you can't trust.
We heard.
requent, which describes something that happens often.
And we also heard delayed, which means something like public transport, comes later than expected.
That's it for this episode of real easy English don't forget to go to our website where you can get a free worksheet to download to test what you've learned It's atbblearningenglish.
com See them goodbye bye.